{
  "worldwar1questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which country made the first declaration of war?",
      "answer1": "A) Germany",
      "answer2": "B) Serbia",
      "answer3": "C) Russia",
      "answer4": "D) Austria-Hungary",
      "correct": "D) Austria-Hungary"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what city was Archduke Franz Ferdinand assassinated?",
      "answer1": "A) Zagreb",
      "answer2": "B) Sarajevo",
      "answer3": "C) Belgrade",
      "answer4": "D) Vienna",
      "correct": "B) Sarajevo"
    },
    {
      "question": "At the beginning of World War I, Bosnia-Herzegovina was part of",
      "answer1": "A) Austria-Hungary",
      "answer2": "B) Yugoslavia",
      "answer3": "C) Serbia",
      "answer4": "D) Croatia",
      "correct": "A) Austria-Hungary"
    },
    {
      "question": "To which other prominent leader was Kaiser Wilhelm II of Germany related?",
      "answer1": "A) Woodrow Wilson of the United States",
      "answer2": "B) Franz Joseph of Austria-Hungary",
      "answer3": "C) Nicholas II of Russia",
      "answer4": "D) Winston Churchill of Britain",
      "correct": "C) Nicholas II of Russia"
    },
    {
      "question": "Germany’s attack upon which country directly provoked Britain to go to war?",
      "answer1": "A) France",
      "answer2": "B) Russia",
      "answer3": "C) Belgium",
      "answer4": "D) Holland",
      "correct": "C) Belgium"
    },
    {
      "question": "Germany’s plan for fighting France and Russia was called",
      "answer1": "A) The Hindenburg Plan",
      "answer2": "B) The Schlieffen Plan",
      "answer3": "C) Operation Barbarossa",
      "answer4": "D) Sturm und Drang",
      "correct": "B) The Schlieffen Plan"
    },
    {
      "question": "What key fortress was the scene of the heaviest fighting during the German invasion of Belgium?",
      "answer1": "A) Liege",
      "answer2": "B) Fort Heineken",
      "answer3": "C) The Hague",
      "answer4": "D) Maginot",
      "correct": "A) Liege"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Russian general lost the Battle of the Masurian Lakes?",
      "answer1": "A) Samsonov",
      "answer2": "B) Kornilov",
      "answer3": "C) Kerensky",
      "answer4": "D) Rennenkampf",
      "correct": "D) Rennenkampf"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which early battle marked the first major German defeat?",
      "answer1": "A) Tannenberg",
      "answer2": "B) The Marne",
      "answer3": "C) Mons",
      "answer4": "D) Masurian Lakes",
      "correct": "B) The Marne"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which best describes Austria-Hungary’s progress early in the war?",
      "answer1": "A) Defeat by Russia; defeat by Serbia",
      "answer2": "B) Victory over Russia; defeat by Serbia",
      "answer3": "C) Defeat by Russia; victory over Serbia",
      "answer4": "D) Victory over Russia; victory over Serbia",
      "correct": "A) Defeat by Russia; defeat by Serbia"
    }
  ]
}